Guide to the James Beard Papers ca. 1950-1980 MSS 263
© 2010 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VII: Events
  - The Oregonian-James Beard Recipe Contest, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - The Parry Center for Children presents James A. Beard: "The Art of Cooking", April 7-8, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - The Parry Center for Children presents James A. Beard: "The Art of Cooking", February 22-24. 1966 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Plays for Living of Southern California: The Art of Cooking, Three Lessons How To, September 1966 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Plays for Living of Southern California presents James Beard: "Let's Have a Party", May 6, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - The Print Club presents James Beard and Julie Dannenbaum in The Art of Cooking, undated (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Restaurant America!, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Reynolds Metal Company, Press Releases, undated (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - Salute to the Ladies featuring James Beard, Architects and Engineers Forum, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - [Scholarship and Guidance Association Demonstration], September 1974-April 1975 (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - "Scholarship and Guidance Association Salutes James Beard", 1975 (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - Seaside Classes 1977, July 11-15, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 51)
  - Sharp Electronics Co., Microwave Oven Spread, James Beard, April 18, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 52)
  - The Smith College Club of Cleveland presents James A. Beard and Ruth Norman: "The Art of Cooking", February 28 - March 2, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 53)
  - The Smith College Club of Cleveland presents James A. Beard and Ruth Norman: "The Art of Cooking", March 5, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 54)
  - Special Four-Lesson Course in Meat Cookery and Carving, March 5, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 55)
  - A Tasting of Great Cooks, flyer, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - Tentative Outline for Menu Series for Woman's Day, undated (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - [University School/Hunting Valley Campus James Beard Benefit], 1975 (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - Western Governors' Conference, Guest Badge, James Andrew Beard, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 59)
  - Women's Committee of the Art Gallery of Toronto presents James A. Beard in "The Art of Cooking", January 28 - February 1, [1963] (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - [Women's Committee of the Portland Symphony Orchestra presents] James Beard, The Art of Fine Cooking, undated (Box 17, Folder 61)
  - Y.P.O., undated (Box 17, Folder 62)
- Series VIII: Printed Material
  This series contains printed materials kept by Beard, including booklets, catalogs, maps, newsletters and posters. It is divided into two subseries by genre and arranged alphabetically.
  - Subseries A: General Printed Material
    - Book Advertisements for Beard, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 63)
    - Booklets, various (Box 17, Folder 64)
    - "Cook Things" catalog, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 65)
    - "Corkscrew", 1957 (Box 17, Folder 66)
    - [Foreign Travel, Maps and Brochures], 1966-73 (Box 17, Folder 67)
    - Gusto International, v.1 no.1, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 68)
    - Miscellaneous, various (Box 17, Folder 69)
    - [Newsletters], 1962-73 (Box 17, Folder 70)
    - Spice Islands recipe pamphlets, undated (Box 17, Folder 71)
  - Subseries B: Menus and Wine Lists
    - American Menus, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Assorted Wine Lists, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Estrada's Inc., Wine Lists, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Foreign Menus, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - French Wines, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - The Happy Cooker, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Menu, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - [Menu, annotated], undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Menu/Program, A Dinner in Honor of Madame Laura Mentzelopoulos, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - [Menus], undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Subseries C: Water Resources Bulletins, 1966-1975
    This subseries contains the Water Resource Bulletins for Pennsylvania from 1966-1975.
    - Water Resource Bulletins, 1966-75 (Box 28)
- Series IX: Clippings
  This series contains clippings from various magaines and newspapers. Materials are arranged alphabetically by publication title, if provided, and then by article title.
  - Subseries A: Print Clippings
    - Beard Clips, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Beard on Bread, review, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Blanching, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Boling - Intro and Eggs, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Boiling - Fish, March 1971 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Boston, "Bob and Madeleine and Lucien and Leo", undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Breads, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Brownstone, Cecily, "He Writes as Well as He Cooks", [1973] (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Charcoal Grilled Fruit, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Corning, Advertisement, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Crab-Lobster Intro. Material, undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Crudites, undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Emulsified Sauces, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Gastronomic Magazine, "Les Classiques de la Cuisine", 1975-76 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Gourmet, "You Asked For It", September 1969 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Gratins, undated (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Harper's Bazaar, "James Beard Gives Monkey Bread", October-December 1974 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Hors D'Oeuvre, undated (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - House and Garden, "Do-it-Yourself Parties", July 1971 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - House and Garden, "5 Master Cooks", July 1970 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - House Beautiful, "Wine and Drink", April 1976 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - New York, "The Insatiable Critic/Gael Greene: A Gourmaniacal Detour", undated (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - [Obituaries, Beard], 1985 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Pan-Frying Vegetables, undated (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Pasta Doughs, undated (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Pastry Doughs and Pastries, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Plain Dealer, "Good Reading Leads to Good Eating", June 17, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Poaching - Custards and Creams, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Poaching - Fruit, undated (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - Poughkeepsie Journal, "Culinary Graduates 109", February 2, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Quick-Breads, undated (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Roasting - Domestic Birds, undated (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - Roasting - Game, undated (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - Roasting - Lamb and Mutton, undated (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - Roasting - Pork, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - [Roasting - Veal], undated (Box 18, Folder 47)
    - Rochester Times Union, "James Beard...A Monument to Good Eating", January 4, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 48)
    - Salads, undated (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - Simmering - Meats, undated (Box 18, Folder 50)
    - Simmering - Soups, undated (Box 18, Folder 51)
    - Souffle, undated (Box 18, Folder 52)
    - Steaming, undated (Box 18, Folder 53)
    - Sunset, "The Curry Mystery", February 1977 (Box 18, Folder 54)
    - Sunset, "Just Strawberries in a Pancake", June 1971 (Box 18, Folder 55)
    - Sunset, [recipes], November 1976 (Box 18, Folder 56)
    - Sunset, [recipes], undated (Box 18, Folder 57)
    - Sunset, "Showstopper Pancake...It's the Famous Dutch Baby in Super Size", January 1977 (Box 18, Folder 58)
    - Sunset, "Sunset's Kitchen Cabinet", June 1972 (Box 18, Folder 59)
    - Sunset, [various], May 1972 (Box 18, Folder 60)
    - Sunset, [various], April 1976 (Box 18, Folder 61)
    - Tea-Brewing and Tea Sandwiches, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 62)
    - [Unknown], "All You Want to Know about Pork and Bacon Farmhouse Recipes", undated (Box 18, Folder 63)
  - Subseries B: Miscellaneous Clippings, various
    This subseries contains primarily newspaper clippings that were originally unarranged. Due to their considerable quantity, they have remained unarranged.
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, various (Box 29)
- Series X: Miscellaneous
  This series contains miscellaneous materials that do not fit within any other series, including writing by others about Beard, writing by others that is not annotated by Beard, lists and blank postcards. The materials are arranged alphabetically.
  - Anuga, Cologne 1951-71: Exhibitors, Visitors and Display Areas, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 64)
  - [l'Archestrate], 1970 (Box 18, Folder 65)
  - [Articles about James Beard], 1964-80 (Box 18, Folder 66)
  - Chez Marguerite, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 67)
  - Cookbooks by James Beard, undated (Box 18, Folder 68)
  - Courtine's Comments on Chapters 1-7, undated (Box 18, Folder 69)
  - Current Biography, vol. 25, no.11, Dec. 1964 (Box 18, Folder 70)
  - "Fine Wines of California", 1964 (Box 18, Folder 71)
  - "How I Cook," [folder annotation], undated (Box 18, Folder 72)
  - [International Series Notes], undated (Box 18, Folder 73)
  - "James Andrew Beard", undated (Box 18, Folder 74)
  - Evan Jones, "James Beard and the World of Food" [annotated], undated (Box 18, Folder 75)
  - Diana Kennedy, Mexican Cooking [annotated], undated (Box 18, Folder 76)
  - Listing of Restaurants in Paris (partial), undated (Box 18, Folder 77)
  - Helen McCully, [1974] (Box 18, Folder 78)
  - Miscellaneous, various (Box 18, Folder 79)
  - [Postcards, blank], undated (Box 18, Folder 80)
  - Restaurants - M/S, undated (Box 18, Folder 81)
  - Restaurants - Specialties, undated (Box 18, Folder 82)
  - Scrapbook, "The Women's Council of the Rochester Museum Association and the Rochester Gas and Electric Corporation presents Mr. James Beard in The Art of Cooking", 1963 (Box 18, Folder 83)
  - Sunset Coast, revised proof [annotated], August 17, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 84)
  - John Noble Wilford, The Mapmakers [annotated index and front matter], [1981] (Box 18, Folder 85)
  - "Wine and Food Matching: A Taste Exploring", undated (Box 18, Folder 86)
- Series XI: Photographs
  This series contains photographs and negatives. The materials in this series are arranged chronologically with all undated photographs at the end.
  - Black & White Photographs, various (Box 19)
  - Color Photographs, various (Box 19)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 20)
- Series XII: Media
  This series contains auido and video materials relating to James Beard's cooking career, including commerical recordings. They are organized into access copies and originals.
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access copies for all media elements may not exist at this time. Please contact a Fales archvist for questions about accessing media.
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - Audio, "View from the 33rd Floor", June 13, 1972 (Box 21, Media ID: 263.0001)
    - Video, "James Beard (Beta II)", undated (Box 21, Media ID: 263.0002)
    - Film, CMA Audio Productions, Heckers Flour, James Beard, 30 sec., undated (Box 21, Media ID: 263.0003)
    - Film, DKG, Inc., Corningware, James Beard, 60 sec. Color, [1973] (Box 21, Media ID: 263.0004)
    - Film, DKG, Inc., Corningware, James Beard, 30 sec. Color, [1973] (Box 21, Media ID: 263.0005)
- OVERSIZE Series I: Manuscripts
  This series contains oversize manuscript materials.
  - Subseries C: Fowl and Game Bird Cookery
    - Fowl and Game Bird Cookery, Galley, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Subseries K: The New Fish Cookery
    - Fish Cookery, Galley, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Fish Cookery, Master Pages, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Subseries L: The New James Beard
    - New James Beard Cookbook, Master Galley, [Harry], November 1, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - New James Beard Cookbook, Master Galley, [Joe], November 5, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - New James Beard Cookbook, Master Pages, [Harry], February 19, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - New James Beard Cookbook, Master Pages, [Joe], March 1981 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - New James Beard Cookbook, Galley, [June 1981] (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - New James Beard Cookbook, Galley, [September 1981] (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - New James Beard Cookbook, Galley, [index], undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - New James Beard Cookbook, Galley Page, Soups, undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
- OVERSIZE Series V: Personal
  This series contains oversize personal materials.
  - Subseries A: General
    - Calendar, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Subseries B: Awards
    - Certificate of Merit, The California Chive Institute, October 9, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Le Medaillon de l'Arbalete, April 13, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - The Order of the Golden Chicken, Delmarva Poultry Industry, June 19, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Special Book Citation, American Foundation of Automation and Employment, Inc., September 22, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- OVERSIZE Series VII: Events
  This series contains oversize materials regarding events.
  - Buffet at The World Trade Center, diagram, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - A Loaf of Bread, a Jug of Wine and James Beard, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - 9. Internationale Koch Kunst - Ausstellung 7. Bundesschau Hotel - Und Gaststaatengewerbe Ehren - Urkunde, October 7, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- OVERSIZE Series VIII: Printed Material
  This series contains oversize printed material.
  - Subseries A: General Printed Material
    - Posters, various (Box Map-case 4E)
      Inlcudes various posters, including a number of Subway Restaurant posters printed after the date of Beard's death in 1985.
    - Andersen Consulting, poster, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - CuisineVu Advertisment, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Family Weekly, November 19, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - A Kernel of Wheat, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Reed Newsletter, Vol. 53, No. 3, October 1, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Serendipity 3, vol. 1, no. 5, August 1975 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Serendipity 3, vol. 1, no. 6, September 1975 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - "The Wizard of Redkey," Kokomo (Ind.) Tribune, June 28, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Subseries C: Water Resources Bulletins
    - Water Resources Bulletin, Bulletin no. 5, cover, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Water Resources Bulletin, Bulletin no. 5 (1 of 3), 1970 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Water Resources Bulletin, Bulletin no. 5 (2 of 3), 1970 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Water Resources Bulletin, Bulletin no. 5 (3 of 3), 1970 (Box 27, Folder 4)
- OVERSIZE Series X: Miscellaneous
  This series contains miscellaneous oversize materials.
  - Blue Print, National Gallery of Art, Washington DC, undated (Box Map-case 4E)
  - [Book Illustrations], undated (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - [Business Week, annotated galley], October 1974 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - [Cookbook Invitation], [1976] (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Discover the Fabulous Foods of Israel with James Beard, undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Fish Chart, undated (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Harper's Bazaar, "Food Gifts" (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook, "James Beard San Francisco 1975" (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - [Untitled Proof], undated (Box 26, Folder 19)
- OVERSIZE Series XI: Photographs
  This series contains overize photographs.
  - [untitled], undated (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - [untitled], undated (Box 26, Folder 21)